Curriculum Vitae

Liang Wang

Full-Stack Web Developer

Citizenship: New Zealand E: Iwang@micro-wang.com
M: +64 21 230 5622 LinkedIn GitHub

About

I'm a full-stack web developer with a passion for creativity and problem-solving.

Recently, I finished an intensive 15-week web development bootcamp from Dev Academy Aotearoa.

This immersive experience has equipped me with a good foundation in full-stack web development with React.js, Express.js, Node.js, TypeScript, SQLite, and Mongo DB.

Before that, I had a few years of successful web development using Angular.js, ASP.Net or ASP.Net Core Web API, and Microsoft SQL Server.

Web application development appeals to me because of the potential to create products that can uplift communities, create experiences, and provide accessibility.

Skills

Technical Skills

- □ Javascript, HTML, CSS, Bootstrap
- □ React.js, Express.js, Node.js, TypeScript
- ☐ Angular.js, C#, DotNet and DotNet Core Web API
- ☐ Microsoft SQL Server, SQLite, Mongo DB
- unit Test with Vitest, API Test with Supertest, UI Component Test with @testing-library.

Communication & Customer Service skills

- □ Interacting with people of diverse backgrounds and cultures and working toward positive outcomes
- Establishing, furthering, and maintaining excellent stakeholder relationships
- Understanding of customer service requirements and timelines
- □ Skilled at identifying needs and ensuring expectations are met or exceeded.

Administration and organizational skills

- Critical thinking and problem-solving skills with fastidious attention to detail
- Ability to perform a range of administrative tasks to the highest standards.
- Streamlining project development and/or job processing
- A proactive team worker can work competently with minimum supervision.

Experiences

Contract Developer, Milly Systems | Auckland

Feb 2023 - Present

- □ Develop the Milly Online Order Web Application using React.js, Express.js, Node.js, TypeScript, and Mongo DB.
- Maintain and support the current Milly application.

Training Course "Full-Stack Web Development" | Dev Academy Aotearoa | June 2023 – Oct 2023

- □ This course included a 15-week full-immersion **Full-Stack Web Development Bootcamp** that closely represents working in a modern development team.
- □ During the course, I learned to solve a lot of challenges and do multiple group projects using React.js, Express.js, Node.js, TypeScript, SQLite, and Mongo DB.

- □ In different group projects, I acted in different roles like Git Keeper, Vibes Watcher, Agile Facilitator, and Product Owner.
- During the course, I also learned and practiced multiple human skills: Cultivating a Growth Mindset, Showing Empathy, Self-Compassion, Active Listening, Giving Feedback, Conflict Resolution, and Retrospective, etc.

Full-Time Analyst/Developer, EAP Services | Auckland

Aug 2017 - Dec 2022

- □ Responsible full-stack web development:
 - a. Design and develop Web Api following the Open API and Swagger UI using Asp.net, Asp.Net Cor, C#, and SQL Server.
 - b. Implement the OAuth2 Identity Systems, and Microsoft MVC Web applications using Asp.Net, C#, and SQL Server.
 - c. Design and develop SPA web applications using Angular.js.
 - f. Practice with OWASP Security and Privacy Guide, enabling the implemented Web API to pass the penetration test conducted by AURA Information Security.
- □ Responsible for internal desktop application development:
 - a. Develop the appointment mailer application using C# and DotNet. The appointment mailer could automatically send appointment confirmations and reminders to the clients.
 - b. Develop the Mail Mover application using C#, DotNet, and Microsoft Outlook. This application could automatically move the received emails to the proper subfolder based on the email types.

Contracted Application Developer, EAP Services | Auckland

Nov 2014 - Aug 2017

- □ Developed the Additional Session Request Process Web Application using C#, ASP.Net MVC, and SQL Server.
- Developed the Desktop Client Request Collect Application using Microsoft Word and VBA
- □ Developed the Online Client Request Collect Application using C#, ASP.Net, and SQL Server.

Education & Associations

- □ Certificate: Full-Stack Web Development Dev Academy Aotearoa
- Professional Developer qualification Microsoft Limited
 (Microsoft Certified Solution Developer and Microsoft Certified Database Administrator)
- □ Bachelor of Commerce Auckland University (Major: Information Systems)
- □ Bachelor of Science Shanghai University (Major: Electronic Physics)

Referees

Available on request